teacherspayteachers.com 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy | Teachers Pay Teachers

Effective Date: January 1, 2020 (See our previous version [here](https://ecdn.teacherspayteachers.com/static/privacypolicy_teacherspayteachers12.pdf))

Teacher Synergy LLC d/b/a Teachers Pay Teachers (referred to in this policy as “Teachers Pay Teachers”, “TpT”, “us”, “we”, or “our”) has adopted the following Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use, and share information from and about you in connection with certain of our products, services, and properties.

Your privacy and security are very important to us at Teachers Pay Teachers.  We’re committed to transparency when it comes to our privacy practices and how we safeguard your information. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) outlines what kinds of information we may ask you for and gather from you as you visit or use TpT, how that information may be used, and under what circumstances certain information might be shared with others. 

This Policy applies to the data you share when you use our “Services” which includes our website at TeachersPayTeachers.com and any affiliated web pages or forms we may create or host (“Site”), our mobile applications (“Apps”), or when you communicate with us. By using or accessing the Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.

This Policy is part of our Terms of Service which you can find [here](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Terms-of-Service).  Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service.

You may print a copy of this Policy by clicking [here](https://ecdn.teacherspayteachers.com/static/tptprivacypolicy2019125.pdf).

The following subsections detail the categories of Personal Information that we collect and have collected over the past twelve (12) months.  For each category of Personal Information, these sections also set out our commercial or business purpose for collecting that Personal Information and the categories of third parties with whom we share that Personal Information. Throughout this Policy, we will refer back to the categories of Personal Information listed below (for example, “Category A. Personal Identifiers”).

## 1\. CATEGORIES OF SOURCES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

##### A. You, For Information You Make Available to Us

Some information collected when you access or use our Services is considered “Personal Information” (or PI).  This is information that relates to or can be used to identify you personally and includes things like your full name, your street address, your phone number, and your email address, and also includes information referred to as “personally identifiable information” or “personal information” under applicable data privacy laws, rules, or regulations.  Other than as provided for in this Policy, we won’t share or disclose this kind of information unless we get your permission. Other information that we collect may not identify you personally. This kind of information may be shared or disclosed in an aggregate form, used to personalize your experience, and so on. 

Visitors.  When you use our Services as a Visitor, we may ask for information about your preferences and interests to personalize your experience and help you find what you need. 

All Members.  To use many aspects of our Services, you’re required to create a TpT account and become a Member.  To become a Member, we require that you pick a unique username, and provide us with your email address so we can contact you.  We may also ask you to tell us your name so we know who you are. 

Finally, we may ask you to share some information about what kind of user you are (your role), your geographic location, what and where you teach, and information about your interests to help us personalize your experience using our Services. 

Sellers.  Members who register for one of our Seller Memberships (“Sellers”), will be required to provide additional contact information and payment information to receive Earnings.  Sellers can choose to use a name other than their given name as a “Store Name.” A Seller’s Store Name, profile image or logo, and any additional information they choose to provide about themselves in their Store profile will be publicly viewable. 

To comply with applicable laws, we may collect federal tax identification information from Sellers, including your social security number or employer identification number, to verify your identity and issue tax documents.

##### B. You, For Information Collected Automatically In Connection With Your Use of Our Services

When you use our Services as a Member or a Visitor, we receive and collect certain information from your browser and your device such as your Internet Protocol address (IP address), device information, operating system, browser type and version, and browser country location.  This information helps us defend against fraudulent activity or attacks, maintain the security of our Services, and improve and personalize your experience. 

We also log data related to how Members and Visitors use our Services, including Cookies (as defined below) that may uniquely identify your visit or account. This log data includes details such as what pages of our Site or App you visit and when, how users navigate through the Site, and visit referral URLs.  This information allows us to better understand how our Services are being used, helps us make improvements, and enables us to personalize your experience with our Services. (Please refer to the Cookies section below for more information about how we use Cookies.) 

From time to time, we may host and provide Members and Visitors the opportunity to participate in contests, sweepstakes, and surveys.  If you choose to participate, you may be asked to provide Personal Information which may be used for purposes necessary to administer the contest, sweepstakes, or survey, or for other marketing purposes.

##### C. Third Parties

We may collect information about you from third parties as permitted by law or through your interaction with third parties we may integrate with from time to time to offer new features and/or services to you (“Third Party Integrations”). We may also receive information about you in connection with our provision of certain services, including for example TPT School Access or gift cards, as well as from some of our service providers who assist us with marketing or promotional services related to how you interact with our websites, applications, products, services, advertisements or communications.

Through an integration with Google Drive, you may have the option to list files directly from your Google Drive in your TpT store (“Resources for Google Apps”), or access Resources for Google Apps directly through your Google Drive account (e.g. resources that you have purchased or added to your TpT account for free).  To enable your use of this integration, you’ll need to give TpT permission to access your Google Drive for the purposes described in this section. If you’re a Seller listing Resources from your Google Drive, we’ll use this access to list in your TpT store files that you choose from your Google Drive account, set file permissions, make copies for each Member who purchases or accesses your Resources for Google Apps for free, and monitor listed files from your Google Drive for deletions, updates, or changes in permissions so we may be able to alert you or impacted Members.  For Members who choose to purchase (or access for free) Resources for Google Apps, we’ll use this access to deliver the Resource to your Google Drive. Use of the integration is subject to Google’s privacy policies — you can find more information about how Google uses your information and what information Google shares with us here.

When you make a purchase through our Services, you’ll need to provide billing and payment information to complete your order. We’ve carefully chosen Service Providers who use Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) compliant practices to process payments (“Payment Processors”). Whether you check out using a credit or debit card, PayPal account, or any other payment method we may support, your payment will be processed directly by our Payment Processor and we’ll never have access to or store your full payment details.

When you use a credit or debit card to pay for your purchases, you’ll be asked to add a credit or debit card payment source (“Payment Card”). When you submit your order, this information will be sent directly to and stored by our Payment Processor. After your payment is processed, the Payment Processor will send TpT some details about the transaction so that we can record your order in our database and provide access to the materials that you purchased. 

The Payment Card you added will be available for future use on your Account.  You can edit or remove this information at any time by navigating to the checkout page or by contacting us for assistance.

If you choose to pay using PayPal, you’ll log in to your PayPal account to complete your order. When PayPal processes your payment, they’ll send us a confirmation with transaction details so we can record your order and provide access to the Resources or services you’ve purchased. We do not collect information about or have access to the specific payment or funding sources or any other financial account details associated with your PayPal account.

## 2\. CATEGORIES OF THIRD PARTIES WITH WHOM WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION

We disclose your Personal Information to the following categories of service providers and other parties:

##### A. Visitors, When You Open a TpT Store

If you choose to become a Seller on TpT, there are some additional contact details we collect to ensure that we can reach you and deliver your earnings payments in the method you choose. You’ll also have a store page and profile, where you can choose to provide additional details about yourself to your customers.  The information you add to your store profile is information that visitors can see. 

The following information is visible to others: 

    * **Your store name**.  This will be the first and last name you provided at registration unless you choose an alternative “Store Name.” You can enter or update your Store Name from the store profile section of your account details here. 

    * **Your location**.  Some location information may be optional to display and can be adjusted in your store profile. 

    * **Your Store Profile image**.  You have the option to upload a photograph, logo, or other image to your Store Profile.

    * **Personal Bio/Other Information**.  You can choose to provide additional information about yourself, your business, and your teaching experience.  Any profile information you provide is visible to those who visit your store and can be edited, updated, or removed by you at any time.  

Other than as described in this Policy, we won’t publicly display or disclose Personal Information about you, such as the email address associated with your account, your street address or phone number, or your earnings and payout information, without your consent.  

##### B. Sellers, When You Place an Order 

When you place an order, your full name, city, state, and zip code will be visible to the Seller whose materials you purchased. Additionally, if you purchase hard goods, the Seller will see the shipping information you entered during checkout to enable them to ship your order. 

##### C. The Public or Other Members, When You Connect, Share, or Communicate With Them

There may be features of our Services which allow you to:

    * Post Content (Resources you upload, and Communications you post such as comments, reviews, questions, or other public messages)

    * Connect, communicate, and share information about yourself with other Members

    * Join and post messages in forums, groups, or communities

    * Link your account to an Organization using TpT for Schools or other Services that allow similar account connections

    * Submit requests for Resources or participate in a shared wish list 

    * Display a public profile, and so on 

By using any of these features, you’re choosing to share information about yourself and your TpT account activity with TpT, the public or with other Members. If you connect with another Member, for example by joining a group or Organization, or by accessing a Resource shared with you by another Member, the Members you interact with may be able to view certain information and activity associated with your account and that interaction.  

##### D. Service Providers

TpT engages the services of third party companies (“Service Providers”) to support and help provide certain features of our Services such as payment processing, customer support, data storage and analysis, visitor tracking and user testing, email messaging, advertising, surveys, Site security and fraud prevention, staff augmentation, hosting and other technology and communications, and other services.  TpT shares data with these Service Providers so that they can perform their services which help deliver our Services more securely, efficiently, and effectively. Service Providers may have access to certain Personal Information in the course of providing their service. Service Providers’ access to your Personal Information is limited to the purpose of providing the services contracted for. Service Providers are not permitted to disclose information we share to other parties (other than their own service providers as necessary) or use your Personal Information for any other purpose. 

TpT may from time to time share aggregate user data with business partners, Service Providers, or other third parties to identify or share trends, usage statistics, and so on. Sharing data in an aggregate form means that no Personal Information, which would allow the recipient of the data to identify you personally, will be shared.  

##### E. Third Parties, In Connection With a Merger, Acquisition, or Other Change of Control

As part of a merger acquisition, bankruptcy or other transaction in which a third party assumes control of our business (in whole or in part), we may transfer the data we have collected, including Personal Information, to the third party.  In such an event, we’ll notify you of that change. In addition, any purchasing company would have to adhere by the terms of this Policy including notifying you before making material changes and giving you the opportunity to opt out. 

##### F. Third Parties, For Information Requests and Legal Obligations

To the extent you make purchases through the Services using an institution, school, or other third-party entity’s credit or debit card, PayPal account, or any other payment method, and that institution, school, or third party requests such information or information related thereto and TpT, in its sole discretion, determines such request is reasonable, we may choose to provide such information or information related thereto to that institution, school, or third party.

Finally, we respect and comply with legal obligations and may release information (including Personal Information and information about your account activities) in cooperation with a law enforcement investigation, in response to a valid legal request such as a court order, legal subpoena, or government inquiry or audit, as part of the process outlined by the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), or to defend, protect, or exercise our legal rights. 

##### G. Other Parties, At Your Direction.

## From time to time, we may partner with other companies or organizations (“Partners’) to offer additional products and services (“Partner Content”). When you buy or use Partner Content, we may share information with our Partners about your order and your account for the purposes of facilitating your use of Partner Content and ensuring delivery of Partner Content to you. We may also share your Personal Information with other parties authorized by you.

## 3\. CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT

##### A. Personal Identifiers

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- Real name

\- Email address

\- Postal address

\- Phone number

\- IP address

\- Account name (e.g., username, alias/store name)

\- Device ID

\- Social security number (as applicable from some Sellers)

\- PayPal ID (email address)

\- Birth year  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You

\- Third parties (e.g. our Service Providers)  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account creation and administration

\- Communications with you for customer support, account-related communication, or marketing

\- To process payments and facilitate purchases made through our Services between Buyers and Sellers 

\- To meet our legal obligations to issue tax documents

\- Website operations, security, and monitoring

\- To issue payments to you (if applicable) 

\- Analytics and marketing

\- To identify you in connection with your account activity (In some cases, this information may be shared or displayed publicly or only to certain other Members in a full or modified form as described in sections I(2)(A)-(C) above.)

\- To ensure the proper operation and security of our Services  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (e.g., payment processors; security and fraud prevention services; hosting and other technology and communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

\- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction  
  
##### B. Customer Records Identified By State Law (Including the California Customer Records Statute (Cal. Civ. Code 1798.80(e))

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- Name

\- Postal address

\- Phone number

\- Social security number (as applicable from some Sellers)

\- Bank account number (as applicable from some Sellers)

\- Last four digits of credit or debit card number

\- Employment  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You

\- Third parties (e.g. our Service Providers)  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account creation and administration

\- Communication with you for customer support, account-related communication, or marketing

\- To meet our legal obligations to issue tax documents

\- To process  payments and facilitate  purchases made through our Services between buyers and sellers

\- To issue payments to you (if applicable)

\- Analytics and marketing

\- To identify you in connection with your account activity (In some cases, this information may be shared or displayed publicly or only to certain other Members in a full or modified form as described in sections I(2)(A)-(C) above.)

\- To enable you to associate your account with a particular school or district  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (e.g., payment processors; security and fraud prevention services; hosting and other technology and communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

\- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction  
  
##### C. Commercial Information

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- Records of the Resources you purchased or downloaded for free from our Site

\- Records of the items you add to a cart or wishlist

\- Your grade level and subject area interests

\- Gift cards purchased or sent

\- ClassFund contributions made or received

\- Search history on our Site

\- Page views on our Site

\- Referral data (the URL from which you arrived on our Site)

\- Ratings or reviews on Resources

\- Payment method used

\- TpT credits earned or used (e.g., from making a purchase after leaving Feedback)

\- Sales and earnings related to your TpT store (if applicable)  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You

\- Third parties (e.g. our Service Providers)  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account administration (e.g., to enable you to access your purchased or downloaded Resources)

\- Order processing

\- Analytics and marketing

\- To ensure the proper operation and security of our Services  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (payment processor; security and fraud prevention services; hosting and other technology and communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

 \- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction   
  
##### ** **

##### D. Internet Or Other Similar Network Activity Information

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- Records of the Resources you purchased or downloaded for free from our Site

\- Records of the items you add to a cart or wishlist

\- Gift cards purchased or sent

\- ClassFund contributions made or received

\- Search history on our Site

\- Page views on our Site

\- Referral data (the URL from which you arrived on our Site)

\- Ratings or reviews on Resources

\- Payment method used

\- TpT credits earned or used (e.g., from making a purchase after leaving Feedback)

\- Sales and earnings related to your TpT store (if applicable)  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You

\- Third parties (e.g. our Service Providers)  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account administration (e.g., to enable you to access your purchased or downloaded Resources)

\- Order processing

\- Analytics and marketing

\- To ensure the proper operation and security of our Services  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (payment processor; security and fraud prevention services; hosting and other technology and communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

\- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction  
  
##### ** **

##### E. Professional Or Employment-Related Information 

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- School association  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You

\- Third Parties (e.g. our Service Providers)  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account and profile information

\- Enabling a user to join a school account

\- Analytics and marketing  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (hosting and other technology and communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

\- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction  
  
##### ** **

##### F. Age Or Date Of Birth

Personal Information We Collect:

| 

\- Birth year  
  
---|---  
  
Sources of this Personal Information:

| 

\- You  
  
Commercial or business purpose for collecting this category of Personal Information:

| 

\- Account creation and administration  
  
Categories of third parties with whom we share this Personal Information:

| 

\- Service Providers (hosting and other technology communications providers; analytics providers; staff augmentation and contract personnel)

\- Acquirors or other parties that might receive Personal Information through a - change of control

\- Other parties at users’ direction  
  
## 1\. COOKIES 

We use cookies and similar technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons (collectively, “Cookies”) to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit and use our Services, to analyze trends, learn about our user base and operate and improve our Services. Cookies are small pieces of data — usually text files — that are placed on your computer, tablet, phone, or similar device when you use that device to visit our Services.  When you visit websites like ours, some information about your visit is stored in Cookies which are used to tailor your experience, surface relevant information, products, and advertisements, and to allow you to pick up where you left off the next time you visit. We may also supplement the information we collect from you with information received from third parties, including third parties that have placed their own Cookies on your device(s). 

By using our Services as a Visitor or Member, you agree to our use of Cookies in the following ways, as well as other similar purposes:  

    * Analytics
    * Marketing
    * Preserving your preferences
    * Personalizing your experience
    * Understanding where our website traffic is coming from 
    * To ensure the security and availability of our Site and our Services

You have the right to decide whether a website can store Cookies on your computer. Depending on the internet browser you use, you may be able to view, manage, delete, and disable Cookies through your browser preferences. If you choose to delete Cookies or to not allow us to use Cookies, some features may not work properly and you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site.  To learn more about how to do this, check out instructions from these browsers:

To find out more information about Cookies, including information about how to manage and delete Cookies, please visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.

The following types of Cookies are used in connection with our Services:

    * Essential Cookies: Essential Cookies are required for providing you with features or services that you have requested. For example, certain Cookies enable you to log into secure areas of our Services.  Disabling these Cookies may make certain features and services unavailable.

    * Functional Cookies: Functional Cookies are used to record your choices and settings regarding our Services, maintain your preferences over time and recognize you when you return to our Services. These cookies help us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name, and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

    * Performance/Analytical Cookies: Performance/Analytical Cookies allow us to understand how visitors use our Services such as by collecting information about the number of visitors to the Services, what pages visitors view on Services and how long visitors are viewing pages on the Services. Performance/Analytical Cookies also help us measure the performance of our advertising campaigns in order to help us improve our campaigns and the Services’ content for those who engage with our advertising. To support and enhance the Services, we use third-party analytics services, including those provided by Google Inc. (“Google”) and Heap Inc. (“Heap”).  Google uses cookies in connection with its Google Analytics services. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Services is subject to the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You have the option to opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page at [www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) or the Google Analytics Opt-out browser Add-on at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). If you would like more information on the type of information Heap collects, please visit Heap’s Website Terms of Use at [https://heap.io/terms](https://heap.io/terms).  

    * Retargeting/Advertising Cookies: Retargeting/Advertising Cookies collect data about your online activity and identify your interests so that we can provide advertising that we believe is relevant to you. For more information about this, please see the section below titled “Information about Interest-Based Advertisements.”

## 2\. INFORMATION ABOUT INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISEMENTS

In some cases, you may see advertisements about our Services on other websites or services which may be targeted to users who have visited our Site or used our Services who fit certain general profile categories or display certain preferences or behaviors (“Interest-Based Ads”). With respect to these Interest-Based Ads, we comply with the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Through the DAA and Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), several media and marketing associations have developed an industry self-regulatory program to give consumers a better understanding of, and greater control over, ads that are customized based on a consumer’s online behavior across different websites and properties. To make choices about Interest-Based Ads from participating third parties, including to opt-out of receiving behaviorally targeted advertisements from participating organizations, please visit the DAA’s or NAI’s consumer opt-out pages, which are located at http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ or www.aboutads.info/choices.

## 3\. GOOGLE ANALYTICS

We use Google Analytics to understand and analyze browsing activity, and for advertising through their AdWords and Remarketing Lists features. Google Analytics may store cookies on your device when you use or access our Services and may use those cookies to display advertisements for our products or Services when you visit other websites. You can find out more about this by reading the information Google provides in this explanation: [How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).  If you don’t want Google Analytics to use cookies when you browse, you can install the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On to prevent Google Analytics from placing cookies on your browser.  You can find out more about this option and how to install the Add-On [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

Your privacy is very important to us.  Other than as provided for in this Policy, we don’t share your Personal Information with third parties without your consent.

## 1\. BUSINESS PURPOSES FOR DISCLOSURES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 

We disclose your Personal Information to Service Providers and other parties for the following business purposes:

    * To perform auditing related to a current interaction and concurrent transactions
    * To detect security incidents, to protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and to prosecute those responsible for that activity
    * To debug to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality
    * To make short-term, transient use of Personal Information that is not used by another party to build a consumer profile or otherwise alter your consumer experience outside the current interaction
    * To perform services on our behalf, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling order and transactions, verifying customer information, processing payments, providing financing, providing advertising or marketing services, providing analytic services, or providing similar services on behalf of the business or service provider
    * To undertake internal research for technological development and demonstration
    * To undertake activities to verify or maintain the quality and safety of a service or device that we own, manufacture, have manufactured for us, or control

Over the past twelve months, we have disclosed the following categories of your Personal Information (which related to the corresponding information in the tables in section I.3 (A-F) above) to Service Providers or other parties for the business purposes listed above:

    * A. Personal identifiers
    * B. Customer records identified by state law
    * C. Protected classification characteristics under state or federal law
    * D. Commercial information
    * E. Internet or other similar network activity information
    * F. Professional or employment-related information
    * G. Age or date of birth 

## 2\. SALES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will not sell your Personal Information and have not done so over the past twelve months.

## 1\. DATA SECURITY

## We seek to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure using appropriate physical, technical, organizational and administrative security measures based on the type of Personal Information and how we are processing that data. You should also help protect your data by appropriately selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism; limiting access to your computer or device and browser; and signing off after you have finished accessing your account.  Although we work to protect the security of your account and other data that we hold in our records, please be aware that no method of transmitting data over the internet or storing data is completely secure. We cannot guarantee the complete security of any data you share with us, and except as expressly required by law, we are not responsible for the theft, destruction, loss, or inadvertent disclosure of your information or content.

## 2\. ACCOUNT SECURITY

Access to your TpT account is secured by the password you choose. For your security, we store only a hashed version of your password. This means that we don’t know your password and your password isn’t visible to us when members of our team view your account. 

To prevent unauthorized access to your account, choose a password that can’t be easily guessed and don’t share your password with anyone else.  Whenever you use a shared computer or other shared device to access your TpT account (for example, a school computer), be sure to log out of your account completely before you leave your workstation, uncheck the “remember me” option at login, and select “no” if the web browser prompts you to save your login credentials.  You’re responsible for keeping your password confidential, and for all activity that occurs under your account, whether or not authorized by you. 

You can change or update your password anytime by visiting your My Account page.  If you forget your password, you can request a reset password link.  

## 3\. DATA RETENTION

## TpT will use your information for the reasons detailed in this Policy in order to deliver our Services to you while your account is active. If you no longer wish to be a Member of our Services, you can close your account with us at any time. If you close your account, your account is placed in an inactive state.  We retain a record of your account information and only use your account information as needed, for example to provide sales data to Sellers you’ve transacted with, to continue to make Resources available to Members who have purchased licenses from you, to comply with a valid legal request or resolve a dispute, or to meet any legal requirements or obligations. We may also continue to include your data as part of ongoing data and usage analysis. We’ll no longer send you marketing or other communications about your account or our Services. You can restore your account at any time by logging in with your email or username and your password. 

TpT for Schools enables increased collaboration and communication between and among teachers and administrators. 

If you’ve linked your TpT account to an Organization using TpT for Schools, your interactions with and activity related to TpT for Schools may be shared with and be visible to other Organization Members and Managers (Organization Users).  Your personal purchases, purchase history, billing information, and personal account details such as your street address and phone number will not be shared. 

Linking your Account.  When you link your TpT account to an Organization, your name and role will be shared with your Organization, and you’ll be added to your Organization’s roster which is visible to other Organization Users.

Requesting Resources.  When you submit a request for Resources, your request will be visible to Organization Users as part of the Organization’s list of pending requests.  TpT may enable your Organization Manager to communicate directly with you about your requests, and send notifications via the email address associated with your TpT account.  When you reply via your personal email account, your email address will be visible to the Organization Manager you’re communicating with.

Receiving Resources.  When a Resource License is shared with you, Organization Users can see that a Resource License has been shared with you, whether you’ve claimed or downloaded that Resource License, and may be able to see other activity related to your use of that Resource. 

Purchases.  When your Organization makes a purchase, those Resources will be added to the Organization’s shared library which is visible to all other Organization Users.

Communicating.  TpT will use the email address associated with your TpT account to send you notifications about your TpT for Schools activity, including communications from your Organization.  By communicating with your Organization by email, you’re sharing your email address with your Organization. 

At TpT, we take children’s privacy very seriously. TpT’s Services are directed at and intended for use by adults only.  We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, you should not use or attempt to use our Services or send any information about yourself to TpT. If we discover that we have collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will take the appropriate measures to promptly remove that information from our Services.

If you believe that TpT may have collected Personal Information about a child under 13, please contact us at support@teacherspayteachers.com to let us know.  We’ll work with you to make sure that information is removed from our Site.

At TpT, it’s important to us that you have the ability to make choices about your personal information, so we provide you with options for managing your account and the information you give us.

## 1\. ACCOUNT INFORMATION

You can view, update, and correct the information you’ve provided about yourself by visiting your My Account page.  You can also remove any of the optional information you’ve provided. Information that is required will be indicated as such and can be updated but cannot be removed. 

If you don’t want to have an account with us anymore, you can close your account at any time.  You can find instructions on how to close your account here, or you can contact us for assistance. 

## 2\. SAVED PAYMENT SOURCE

Your saved Payment Card record can be edited or deleted from the checkout page.  If you need assistance, you can contact us and we’ll be happy to remove any saved Payment Card records for you. 

## 3\. EMAIL PREFERENCES

TpT uses your contact information to communicate with you about our services and to provide notifications related to your account or activity. Certain communications related to your account or your activity are required and you can’t opt out of receiving them. These include, but aren’t limited to, purchase-related notifications, notifications related to changes that have been made to your login credentials or account details, and legal notifications. Other communications may not be required such as announcements about our Services, newsletters and messages with information you might be interested in, and other marketing and promotional messages (“Optional Communications”). You can manage your preferences related to Optional Communications in the Email Preferences section of your account, or by using the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Optional Communication you receive.

## 4\. OTHER 

If you choose to create a public profile, or post Communications, any information you post will be visible by other Users and the public. You can edit and update Communications you’ve posted and information provided in your public profile. You can delete your public profile at any time.

If you are a California resident, you have the rights outlined in this section.  Please see the “Exercising Your Rights” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Policy and you are a California resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Information shall control to the extent of such conflict.  If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following applies to you, please contact us at [Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com](mailto:Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com).

## 1\. ACCESS

You have the right to request certain information about our collection and use of your Personal Information over the past twelve months.  We will provide you with the following information:

    * The categories of Personal Information that we have collected about you
    * The categories of sources from which that Personal Information was collected
    * The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling your Personal Information
    * The categories of third parties with whom we have shared your Personal Information
    * The specific pieces of Personal Information that we have collected about you

If we have disclosed your Personal Information for a business purpose over the past twelve months, we will identify the categories of Personal Information shared with each category of third party recipient.

## 2\. DELETION

You have the right to request that we delete the Personal Information that we have collected from you.  Under the CCPA, the right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, we may need to retain your Personal Information to provide you with the Services or complete a transaction or other action you have requested, or to comply with our legal obligations. If your deletion request is subject to one of these exceptions, we may deny your deletion request.

## 3\. EXERCISING YOUR RIGHTS

To exercise the rights described above, you must send us a request that (1) provides sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom we have collected Personal Information, and (2) describes your request in sufficient detail to allow us to understand, evaluate and respond to it. Each request that meets both of these criteria will be considered a “Valid Request.” We may not respond to requests that do not meet these criteria. We will only use Personal Information provided in a Valid Request to verify you and complete your request. You do not need an account to submit a Valid Request.

We will work to respond to your Valid Request within 45 days of receipt. We will not charge you a fee for making a Valid Request unless your Valid Request(s) is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that your Valid Request warrants a fee, we will notify you of the fee and explain that decision before completing your request.

You may submit a Valid Request using the following methods:

    * Email us at: [Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com](mailto:Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com)
    * Submit a request using our [Contact Us form](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Contact?t=ccpa)

You may also authorize an agent (an “Authorized Agent”) to exercise your rights on your behalf.  To do this, you must provide your Authorized Agent with written permission to do so, and we may request a copy of this written permission from your Authorized Agent when they make a request to exercise your rights on your behalf.

## 4\. WE WILL NOT DISCRIMINATE AGAINST YOU FOR EXERCISING YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE CCPA

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights under the CCPA. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws (including the CCPA) with varying prices, rates, or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of Personal Information that we receive from you.

## 5\. OTHER PRIVACY RIGHTS 

Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you can visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

## 1\. NEVADA RESIDENT RIGHTS

If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt out of the sale of certain Personal Information to third parties who intend to license or sell that Personal Information. Please note that we do not currently sell your Personal Information as sales are defined in Nevada Revised Statutes Chapter 603A. You can indicate your preferences with respect to this right by contacting us at [Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com](mailto:Privacy@TeachersPayTeachers.com) with the subject line “Nevada Do Not Sell Request” and providing us with your name and the email address associated with your account.  

There are places throughout our Services, such as advertisements and other links, where you can access websites owned and operated by third parties. The terms of this Policy apply only to our Services and websites and do not apply to any third party websites that may be linked to or accessible from our Services. We can’t guarantee the privacy and security standards of other websites, so if you choose to access these third party links, you’ll want to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and other terms applicable to those sites.  

The Content uploaded or posted to our Services is made available at the direction of our Members. We are not responsible for the Content, including any disclosures of Personal Information by our Members. If you believe that any Content posted on our Services violates your personal privacy rights, please notify us at [support@teacherspayteachers.com](mailto:support@teacherspayteachers.com) or by using our [Contact Us form](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Contact?aref=lmyc3hcb).

From time to time, we’ll update this Policy in accordance with the process and rules in our [Terms of Service](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Next-Terms-of-Service?aref=lmyc3hcb).  We will alert you to changes by placing a notice on the Site, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. Please note that if you haven’t provided us with your correct email address, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes. Use of information we collect is subject to the Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

For any questions you have about this Policy, the ways in which we collect and use your Personal Information, or your choices and rights regarding such use, or if you need assistance with your account, you can reach us anytime using the following methods:

    * Submit a question using our [Contact Us form](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Contact?aref=lmyc3hcb)
    * Email us at [Privacy@teacherspayteachers.com](mailto:Privacy@teacherspayteachers.com)
    * Write to us at 111 E. 18th St., 11th Floor, New York, NY 10003

You may also find the answer to your question in our [FAQs](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Help?aref=lmyc3hcb).
